<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description>Stylish Jekyll Theme</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>The Beginning</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This past Friday marked the conclusion of my first week in Software Engineering. Already, I’ve been consumed with an &lt;strong&gt;overwhelming amount of firsts&lt;/strong&gt;. First time learning Python and JavaScript, first time utilizing continuous integration tools, and in the grand scheme of this course, the first time I’m going to contribute to a Full Stack Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I have found to be the end goal of this course can all be summerized in the context of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Extreme-Programming-Installed-Ron-Jeffries/dp/0201708426&quot;&gt;THIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; book. It gives a remarkabley beautiful overview of what exactly goes into extreme programming projects. In a nutshell, the full cycle is discussed, from customer need, to designing and timing, to implementation, to the importance of constant testing, and finally, to deployement. As students with very little real-world job experience, it was a pleasure to sneek a peak of aspects of software enginnering &lt;strong&gt;other than programming&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, I see the motives of this book reflected in our first project, the Collatz Conjecture. Although the problem itself is very trivial, the guidelines to complete the project are on a different spectrum and end up teaching us something grander: the importance of utilizing what tools are available to us. Of course there is version control, where we track the stages of our project using Git and GitHub. Then there is testing, where we make use of Python’s Unit Testing Framework (unittest) and Travis CI as our integration tool, both of which test for correctness. Coupled with that is Python’s Coverage tool, which is a measurement of the quality of your test cases. Finally, all work is documented using PyDoc. It goes to show that &lt;strong&gt;there are stages to programming&lt;/strong&gt; rather than just diving in. There’s the conception of the idea, the setup, creating the right tests, breaking those tests, and documenting the reasonings behind one’s implementation.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The structure of this class is great. You hit the ground running. So far, I have learned two languages and a plethora of tools, which is by far more than what I was expecting. Professor Downing is a remarkable lecturer for many reasons: his well-spoken candid manner, his intent to initiate and force collaboration from his students, and keeping himself (and his students) exposed to latest tools available to developers. It keeps the spirit of the CS community alive … and keeps me on my toes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip of the Week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using version control, like Git, can become overwhelming, especially when you start managing multiple branches and have merge conflicts. StackOverflow is a wonderfull discussion form, but can be verbose and cumbersome with differnt responses. In the grand scheme of things, you will save yourself if you take the time to follow the advice on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/advanced-overview&quot;&gt;Atlassian Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, when using Git, the simple command “git status” can become your friend.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>/general/2015/06/12/hello-world.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/2015/06/12/hello-world.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
